So I'm sure you've got it by now that this week's
所以现在我确定你已经知道本周的
videos are all about pivot tables. But what we have done so far is we've only
视频都是关于数据透视表的。 但到目前为止， 我们所做的只不过是
looked at the analysis
探讨了一张工作表的
of one worksheet. We've only dug into
分析 。 我们只深入探讨了
this register log, but there's more
注册登录表，但还有更多的
in our spreadsheet, right? We have the list of beers. In addition to the times
在我们的电子表格吧？ 除了时间的列表，我们还有 啤酒的列表
and the quantities, we also have different beers and
和其数量，我们也有 不同类型的啤酒而
they are related in a sense to the beers in our beer list and we have more
它们在某种意义上是与我们啤酒单中的啤酒有关，我们在那里拥有更多的
information there.
信息。
Because we can we have a brewery here, we know the type of the beer, we know
因为我们在这里有一个啤酒厂，我们知道了啤酒的类型，我们知道
alcohol percentage, so we would like to analyze that. For instance,
酒精度数，所以我们想对这做分析。 例如，
what is the alcohol percentage of our most sold beer or something like that.
我们卖得最好的啤酒的酒精度数是多少或之类的东西。
But we can't do that now, because we don't have that information in our pivot table.
但是我们现在还办不到，因为我们的数据透视表里没有那些信息 。
about how to combine multiple worksheets together into
关于如何把多个工作表 组合在一起 成为
an overview pivot table.
一个概述数据透视表 。 当然，这门课里我们可以做的是
maybe you were yelling this again to your computer screen,
也许你又在电脑屏幕前大声喊出
is we could use a VLOOKUP. So if you want to have the brewery associated with
我们可以使用VLOOKUP（）。 所以，如果你想让啤酒厂与
each beer,
每个啤酒做相关连结
we can just use a VLOOKUP. We set, of course, the final parameter to FALSE, you
我们可以只用VLOOKUP（）。 就目前为止你所知道的，
know that by now,
我们当然是设最后的参数为FALSE。
and then we have the brewery for each beer. And now we could do an analysis
然后我们就有了关于每个 啤酒的啤酒厂资料。 而现在，我们可以
on the breweries. However, if we would continue this
对啤酒厂做一个分析。 但是，如果我们将 继续将这一分析
we haul in the brewery but we also haul in
带入啤酒厂，我们也 能够进一步分析酒精度数，
the alcohol percentage, and the type, and the category of beer,
类型 和啤酒的类型
we get a lot of duplication. Basically we're going to repeat the entire beers
我们得到很多复制。 基本上我们要在
worksheet
注册登录工作表重制作整个啤酒工作表
in the register log worksheet. What I hope you take away from this course is that
我希望 你从这门课程学到的是
you should really be aware
你应该要注意复制
of duplication. If you are doing the same thing
如果你正在做同样的 事
a lot of times, probably you are not doing things in the easiest way.
很多时候也许你不是使用最简便的方法处理事情。
Because I'm sure there is always a way to do things once,
因为我相信总有办法将事情一次处理完毕，
and to repeat the analysis from there. So I hope,
并从中进行重复分析。 所以我希望
maybe in a year or two and you're working on your spreadsheet
也许一年或两年内，你正在制作电子表格
and you think: "Hey, I've done this before, an hour ago".
你会想：嘿， 一个小时前我刚做过。
I hope you remember me:
我希望你记住我的话：
Duplication is not a good idea, there should be an easier way
复制并不是一个好主意， 应该有一个更简单的方法
to do this. I'm going to present that easier way to you in this video.
来处理。 我要在这个视频里向你介绍更简单的方法 。
So I promised you all the way back, like three videos ago, that this
就像以前的三个视频那样我向你保证的
'adding things to the data model' is really important and I'm going to come back
“添加东西到数据模型”相当重要，而我会回到
to that promise right now. So we've added this data
这个保证上来。 所以我们增加 此数据
to the data model, it is stored somewhere.
到数据模型，它被存储在某处。
If we're going to do the same thing with our beers,
如果我们要对我们的啤酒做同样的事情，
we're making a pivot table of the beer list
我们得把啤酒列表做成一个数据透视表
and, again, we're adding this data to the data model,
而这次，我们又再一次地把这数据添加到数据模型里，
we're putting it in another worksheet. I've made a worksheet called BeersPivot,
我们把它放在另一个工作表 。 我已做了一个命名为的啤酒数据透视表的工作表。
and this is where we place the pivot table for the beer list.
而这正是我们放置啤酒列表的地方。
So what you see here now, exactly as we saw
所以现在在这里所看到的，也正是我们之前所看到的
in the previous pivot table, we have all the fields from our worksheet there,
在以前的数据透视表,在那里列有我们全部工作表，
we can do nice analysis on it like
我们可以对它做很好的分析
the brewery, what is the number of different beers from this brewery?
啤酒厂，这个啤酒厂出产的不同啤酒的数量是多少？
We can sort and then we can see this first brewery,
我们可以进行排序，然后我们就可以看到第一个啤酒厂—
the Midnight Sun Brewing Company, has 51 different beers.
午夜太阳酿造公司有51 不同的啤酒。
But what we're actually calculating now
但我们现在实际计算的
is the number of beers in the beer list,
是在啤酒列表中啤酒种类的数量，
in this worksheet there's no relation yet
这工作表尚未和
to the beers that we in our bar are actually selling.
我们在酒吧实际上卖的啤酒有相关。
This is not the beers we're counting,
这不是我们所计算的啤酒，
we're counting the beers from the beer list. So
我们要计算啤酒列表上的啤酒。 所以
now here's where the data model comes in. If we go to all data
现在，这里是数据模型可以使用之处。 如果我们查看所有数据，
and we see that in addition to the data from this worksheet that we are analysing
我们看到的是，除了我们正在分析的工作表的数据
also the information from the register log is there,
还有登录表单。
and this is because we have previously added this data
这是因为我们先前有添加该数据
to the data model. We can use the same data
到数据模型中。 我们可以从我们的第二个数据透视表里的第一数据透视表中
from the first pivot table in our second pivot table,
使用相同的数据，
because we previously added this to the data model that's what matters here.
因为我们先前添加了这个到数据模型中，这是这里最重要的。
So now we can change our analysis we can say: Hey,
所以，现在我们可以改变我们的分析，我们可以 说：嘿，
we don't want to have the number of beers from
我们不希望啤酒列表有啤酒数目，
the beer list. No, we want to have the number of beers from the register.
我们希望登录表中有啤酒的数量。
That's the field that we want to add. Let's take that field,
这就是我们要添加的字段。 让我们保留字段
throw this away,
把这丢掉
and we drag in the number of beers. Now something interesting happens.
拖入啤酒的数量。 现在，有趣的事情发生了。
Excel says: Hey, I don't know how to do this.
Excel说：嘿，我不知道该怎么处理这个。
These two things aren't related. Basically what Excel is asking us is:
这两件事情没关联。 基本上Excel问我们的是：
I don't know that VLOOKUP, that VLOOKUP that we manually made in the beginning.
我不知道VLOOKUP（），而这个VLOOKUP（） 就是我们最初手动加的。
what the exact relation between those two fields is.
那两个字段之间的确切关系是什么。
And you can see here how we do that, the things we were coupling in the VLOOKUP
你可以在这里看到我们是如何操作的， 我们在VLOOKUP()中进行耦合的项
we couple them together again. And if we do that now,
我们把它们耦合，而如果我们现在进行耦合操作的话
we sort our data, then we can see what
我们给我们的数据进行排序，这让我们可以看到
brewery sells the most popular beer in our actual bar.
在我们的酒吧里销量最好的啤酒是产自哪家啤酒厂的。
So we've made that connection between those two worksheets by
因此，我们已经取得了 这两个工作表 之间的关连，我们把
adding both of them to the data model and then telling Excel
这两者添加到数据模型里 然后告诉Excel
the beer field in our register log is related to the name field
我们登录表单的啤酒字段与啤酒列表的名称字段有相关
in our beer list and then we can make an analysis based on
，然后我们就可以基于两种不同的工作表使用数据透视表进行分析。